<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Seeing-Through-Death</title>
    <link href="/2025/08/01/Seeing-Through-Death/"/>
    <url>/2025/08/01/Seeing-Through-Death/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Seeing-through-death"><a href="#Seeing-through-death" class="headerlink" title="Seeing through death"></a>Seeing through death</h1><h2 id="How-I-view-death-and-why"><a href="#How-I-view-death-and-why" class="headerlink" title="How I view death, and why"></a>How I view death, and why</h2><hr><h3 id="THAT-NIGHT"><a href="#THAT-NIGHT" class="headerlink" title="THAT NIGHT"></a>THAT NIGHT</h3><p>I woke up as normal, went to school like any other day, came back, and lay on my bed. It was a normal night — nothing felt different. It was quiet, even comforting.</p><p>Suddenly, a sense of terror caught me up. I didn’t know why at first, but I suddenly became afraid of death. Once I thought about death, which will happen to me after several years, and I will pass away with nothing left, I was terrified—no matter what I did, I would eventually vanish.</p><p>I imagined our lifespan as a long, long hallway with a hundred rooms, each connected with a door. Every door represented a year in our lives. Moving forward, we pass through each door, one after another, with no choices. Inside the rooms, there are fantastic scenes, colorful sights, and wonderful people.</p><p>But the last chamber is different. It was filled with nothing but pure, endless darkness.<br>And a lock on the door.</p><p>That night, I couldn’t help thinking of it. I was sinking in fear, desperately thinking of a way to escape death.</p><p>That was a night that happened in my middle school. I am not as afraid of it as I used to be, but sometimes, I still question myself: Am I still scared of it? To answer that, maybe I should think about the meaning of death.  </p><hr><h3 id="MEANING-OF-DEATH"><a href="#MEANING-OF-DEATH" class="headerlink" title="MEANING OF DEATH"></a>MEANING OF DEATH</h3><p>People always say that living has its meaning — to achieve some goal. But when it comes to death, there rarely seems to be an answer to this question. Should death be seen as a meaningless event, as it brings everything to an end?</p><p>I don’t think so.</p><hr><h4 id="A-New-Beginning"><a href="#A-New-Beginning" class="headerlink" title="A New Beginning"></a>A New Beginning</h4><p>Death, understood by a biology student, is the natural, irreversible cessation of all biological functions that sustain life. However, does the stop of the physical body also mean the end of the mind?</p><p>I have listened to a lecture about the philosophy of death. In the lecture, the professor claims that discussing “what is after death” is meaningless. Because, in his view, death itself is the absolute end of everything.</p><p>I find it hard to accept that. It is not a flawless answer. No one knows what follows death, how can we be sure there’s nothing beyond it?</p><p>Indeed, our body decays, but the question remains: Where does our mind go?</p><p>Whether it is in the form of matter or energy, it is just not convincing to say that it disappears simply.</p><p>And if the mind still exists — if some part of us continues to exist — couldn’t that be a beginning instead of an end? We left our body, our memory, and everything we had behind and persists in a brand new form.</p><p>Then why am I afraid of it?</p><p>Even death is no longer an end, accepting death means saying goodbye to all our former lives. To let go of the life I have built, people I love, and the countless things I have yet to do. There are so many things I want to do — as the world keeps changing, new opportunities will always emerge. Also, since we do not know what it will be like in the afterworld, maybe it could be paradise, but it could also be hell.</p><p>Maybe I was afraid of death because of that.</p><hr><h4 id="A-Goodbye-Said-with-Dignity"><a href="#A-Goodbye-Said-with-Dignity" class="headerlink" title="A Goodbye Said with Dignity"></a>A Goodbye Said with Dignity</h4><p>In society, a person’s death could not be decided by anyone — even the person themselves. Ba Jin, a famous writer in China, was suffering in his last moments. Ba Jin had been diagnosed with Parkinson’s disease and several other afflicting diseases. Toward the end, he needed to insert a gastric tube, cut open his trachea, and breathe with a breathing machine. He wished to give up this torturous treatment, but neither his family nor the hospital allowed it.</p><p>Everyone wanted him to be alive.</p><blockquote><p>“Longevity, to me, is a form of suffering.”</p></blockquote><p>In such circumstances, death becomes more than an end. It becomes a release of soul, a chase of liberty, and a valediction said with dignity. And yet, the patients usually have no choice about their lives — their family does not want them to leave.</p><p>If you have a terminal disease — not the kind that will kill you instantly, but the one that will torture you restlessly — will you choose to die? Someone has asked me this question.</p><p>I didn’t answer.</p><p>Most people I asked chose to die. The torture was simply too much to endure.</p><p>In the end, the question is:</p><blockquote><p>Which is more terrifying — suffering, or death?</p></blockquote><p>And for me:  </p><blockquote><p>Do I fear death more than I fear suffering?</p></blockquote><p>Maybe I am still afraid of death.</p><hr><h3 id="LIVE-FOR-DEATH-DIE-FOR-LIVING"><a href="#LIVE-FOR-DEATH-DIE-FOR-LIVING" class="headerlink" title="LIVE FOR DEATH, DIE FOR LIVING"></a>LIVE FOR DEATH, DIE FOR LIVING</h3><p>Kathryn Mannix, a palliative care doctor, used to feel frustrated and fearful about the death of her patients. But as she accompanied more patients passing through their last moments, she became less afraid of death itself and viewed it as a natural process. Constant exposure to death didn’t numbed her, but make her wiser about the meaning of life.</p><p>As we live longer and longer, we will discover various scenes, more colorful worlds, and greater chances in the future. In those rooms, we may understand:</p><blockquote><p>Only faith endures, eternal as the sun and moon.</p></blockquote><p>In the last few rooms, we may feel:</p><blockquote><p>Were youth mine once more, I’d trade an ounce of gold for an ounce of wind.</p></blockquote><p>But without regret.</p><p>To embrace the darkness in the final room.</p><p>Perhaps someone just forgot to turn on the light.</p><p>Maybe I will not afraid of death.</p><hr><p><strong>Thank you for reading.</strong><br><em>Leave a comment if you want.</em><br><em>Btw leave it in Cliff’s official website.</em></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>杂言</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>原创</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>A-Journey-of-Notes,-Biology,-and-a-5</title>
    <link href="/2025/07/31/A-Journey-of-Notes-Biology-and-a-5/"/>
    <url>/2025/07/31/A-Journey-of-Notes-Biology-and-a-5/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="A-Journey-of-Notes-Biology-and-a-5"><a href="#A-Journey-of-Notes-Biology-and-a-5" class="headerlink" title="A Journey of Notes, Biology, and a 5"></a>A Journey of Notes, Biology, and a 5</h1><p>It was a sunny morning. The sun was shining through the windows onto the tables. I took a brand new notebook just for AP Bio, and went into the class of 403. People were robbing the seats (which continued for about 5-6 periods) and arguing who was the first at that seat.</p><p>I sat down and looked around. Someone is discussing the contents of APbio that they previewed before. Someone opening the notebooks with some learning notes they took in summer vacation.</p><p>Suddenly, the bell rang. The classroom fell into silence. Ms. Yuan came in with a smile.<br>……</p><img src="/2025/07/31/A-Journey-of-Notes-Biology-and-a-5/Notebook.jpg" class="" title="My Biology Notebook"><h2 id="After-all-what-did-we-learn"><a href="#After-all-what-did-we-learn" class="headerlink" title="After all, what did we learn?"></a>After all, what did we learn?</h2><p>In a nutshell, AP Biology is a brief introduction to the wonderful world of biology. It’s designed to be equivalent to a first-year college introductory biology course for science majors. If you are a student who enjoys biology or wants a challenge, choose AP bio!</p><p>AP biology, different from the biology courses of IB and A-level, focuses on 8 units:  </p><ol><li>Chemistry of Life  </li><li>Cell Structure &amp; Function  </li><li>Cellular Energy  </li><li>Cell Communication &amp; Cell Cycle  </li><li>Heredity  </li><li>Gene Expression &amp; Regulation  </li><li>Evolution &amp; Natural Selection  </li><li>Ecology</li></ol><img src="/2025/07/31/A-Journey-of-Notes-Biology-and-a-5/1.jpg" class="" title="Contents of AP biology (From: Cliff’s AP biology Notes)"><p>Each unit has a different portion in the AP test. From this year’s students’ comments, the hardest parts of the whole course are units 4, 6, and 7. Fortunately, unit 7 is less included in the test. (But 6 and 4 are the hardest according to our classmates, so you need to care more about that hahahahaha)</p><p>AP biology requires you to understand more than recite. You need to <strong>LISTEN TO THE TEACHER</strong> in class and make sure you understand all the knowledge points. I really recommend taking notes on a <strong>NOTEBOOK</strong> instead of a MacBook (you can do so if you think you have good note-taking skills on computers) since you can have the writing feelings that enhance your memory. However, taking notes should never be the only thing you are doing. The teacher’s speaking speed is always faster than you write, and missing points is just a matter of time.</p><p><em>(Advertisement: Use CLIFF’s AP Biology NOTES on <a href="https://dawn-countess-e09.notion.site/AP-Biology-Notes-1a83a033920080bfaeeadd0b7446bfb4?source=copy_link">Notion</a> — a fantastic note-reviewing place just for AP biology made by Cliff. You can also access Cliff’s AP Biology Notes on Ms. Yuan’s website <a href="https://xyyuan.fun/">xyyuan.fun</a> — about → Friendly links → Cliff’s Notes for AP Biology. It’s free and comfortable to use.)</em></p><p>Of course, only listening and taking notes are far from perfect. <strong>PRACTICE</strong> is important. You can stick to the teacher’s assignments after class and the mock exams by the school, but some extra tests for personal mistake-discovering will be beneficial. I prefer to use ancient (at least old) AP tasks’ questions to find my mistakenly understood parts.</p><p>Learn from mistakes is what I learned more than biology.<br>In March, I was frustrated by my FRQ scores. I kept thinking, “Why can’t I do better?” So I went to Ms. Yuan for help. She pointed out that I often wrote less and skipped important reasoning steps in my reasoning. I was focusing too much on the conclusion, but not showing how I got there. After that, I changed my approach to answering FRQs. Instead of just writing what I thought was the answer, I made sure to explain the reasoning behind it step by step, like guiding the reader through my thought process. Read the answers after I wrote them — it’s easy, but it really worked — my scores started improving. Eventually, I was able to hit a high score on the FRQs. Remember, always connect your reasoning. Think of it like telling a story: from cause → mechanism → result.</p><p>Yes, you’ll reach that “OMG! The AP test is coming!” stage in April. At that point, learning is mostly done — it’s time to review. Go through your old mistakes, ask your classmates, and if you still don’t understand something, ask your teacher.<br>A lifesaver: Read the official AP Biology exam outline on College Board. It clearly tells you what will appear on the test paper and what won’t. By focusing only on the essentials, you can study more efficiently and score higher with less effort.</p><p>Looking back, AP Biology was more than just a difficult course. It was a journey full of pressure, teamwork, and personal growth. On the morning of the test, we were nervous as we stayed together in a hotel, reviewing everything we could. But in the end, all the hard work paid off. I got a 5, and many others did great, too. If you’re planning to take AP Biology next year, be ready to work hard — but it will be worth it. You’ll learn a lot, and not just about biology.  </p><h2 id="To-biology"><a href="#To-biology" class="headerlink" title="To biology!"></a><strong>To biology!</strong><br><img src="/2025/07/31/A-Journey-of-Notes-Biology-and-a-5/heying.jpg" class=""></h2><h2 id="Q-A-session"><a href="#Q-A-session" class="headerlink" title="Q&amp;A session:"></a>Q&amp;A session:</h2><img src="/2025/07/31/A-Journey-of-Notes-Biology-and-a-5/nan.jpg" class=""><p><strong>1. Is it very very very hard?</strong><br>As long as you take notes and learn carefully, it will be a great experience of diving into the world of biology.</p><img src="/2025/07/31/A-Journey-of-Notes-Biology-and-a-5/zuoye.jpg" class=""><p><strong>2. How much assignments?</strong><br>Not massive, quite pressure-less amount. However, it is very important to finish it with quality.</p><img src="/2025/07/31/A-Journey-of-Notes-Biology-and-a-5/haoshi.jpg" class=""><p><strong>3. How much time does it take?</strong><br>For me, about 2 hours when you have biology class and 1 hour without biology class. For the last week before the test, maybe more hours are needed, according to how many APs you are taking.</p><img src="/2025/07/31/A-Journey-of-Notes-Biology-and-a-5/zhunbei.jpg" class=""><p><strong>4. How to be prepared for the exam?</strong><br>Practice, question teachers and classmates, and read the outline. Take all mistakes seriously, as the scoring was strict and easy to lose points.</p><img src="/2025/07/31/A-Journey-of-Notes-Biology-and-a-5/gongli.jpg" class=""><p><strong>5. GPA high or not?</strong><br>A bad question.<br>But it’s actually high. By answering questions and doing well on tasks, you will get bio cash, which can add points to your GPA.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Biology</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>原创</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>测试文章</title>
    <link href="/2025/07/29/test/"/>
    <url>/2025/07/29/test/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="First-Thoughts"><a href="#First-Thoughts" class="headerlink" title="First Thoughts"></a>First Thoughts</h1><p><em>By Cliff – July 29, 2025</em></p><hr><p>Hello and welcome.</p><p>This is a test page — a beginning, a placeholder, a gentle step into a space I plan to shape over time.</p><h2 id="What-is-this"><a href="#What-is-this" class="headerlink" title="What is this?"></a>What is this?</h2><p>A blog? Maybe. A notebook? Possibly.<br>Let’s just say it’s a space where thoughts go when they’re ready to be written down.</p><p>I’m Cliff, and this is <strong>HeadlessGravel</strong>.</p><h2 id="The-Name"><a href="#The-Name" class="headerlink" title="The Name"></a>The Name</h2><p>You might wonder — why <em>HeadlessGravel</em>?</p><p>HeadlessGravel is just a name for Cliff to call himself online.</p><h2 id="What’s-Coming"><a href="#What’s-Coming" class="headerlink" title="What’s Coming"></a>What’s Coming</h2><p>This page will probably evolve.<br>Expect:</p><ul><li>Short reflections  </li><li>Notes on books, ideas, problems  </li><li>Maybe some code or design  </li><li>Definitely some silence between posts</li></ul><h2 id="Final-Words-for-now"><a href="#Final-Words-for-now" class="headerlink" title="Final Words (for now)"></a>Final Words (for now)</h2><p>Thanks for reading.<br>Leave expectations behind, and enjoy the drift.</p><hr><p><em>© 2025 Cliff &#x2F; HeadlessGravel</em></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>杂言</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>原创</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hello World</title>
    <link href="/2025/07/29/hello-world/"/>
    <url>/2025/07/29/hello-world/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to <a href="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</a>! This is your very first post. Check <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/">documentation</a> for more info. If you get any problems when using Hexo, you can find the answer in <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/troubleshooting.html">troubleshooting</a> or you can ask me on <a href="https://github.com/hexojs/hexo/issues">GitHub</a>.</p><h2 id="Quick-Start"><a href="#Quick-Start" class="headerlink" title="Quick Start"></a>Quick Start</h2><h3 id="Create-a-new-post"><a href="#Create-a-new-post" class="headerlink" title="Create a new post"></a>Create a new post</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo new <span class="hljs-string">&quot;My New Post&quot;</span><br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/writing.html">Writing</a></p><h3 id="Run-server"><a href="#Run-server" class="headerlink" title="Run server"></a>Run server</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo server<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/server.html">Server</a></p><h3 id="Generate-static-files"><a href="#Generate-static-files" class="headerlink" title="Generate static files"></a>Generate static files</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo generate<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/generating.html">Generating</a></p><h3 id="Deploy-to-remote-sites"><a href="#Deploy-to-remote-sites" class="headerlink" title="Deploy to remote sites"></a>Deploy to remote sites</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo deploy<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/one-command-deployment.html">Deployment</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
